ana estrada

software developer www.anaestrada.es

behance.net/aemartos github.com/aemartos linkedin.com/in/aemartos

about

Software developer, graphic and web designer specialized in UI-UX, photographer, amateur typographer, deeply creative, small-time cinephile, shower singer, hardened reader, geocacher, incessant traveller, chameleon and autodidact by nature, oversociable and tireless fighter.

skills

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, ES6, TypeScript, jQuery, React, Redux, AJAX, Apollo GraphQL, Next.js, Nest.js, Node.js, MongoDB, SQL & Express.

Software: Adobe CC (Photoshop, Premiere, After Effects, Illustrator, InDesign, XD, Audition...), Sketch, Principle, Glyphs, iWork.

Languages: Spanish (native) and English (high level).
Cambridge English: FCE.

awards

IronHack Hackshow 2019: Best Web Development project.

TadHack 2018: <u>Drugon</u>
1st local award by UPM.
2nd award by Kairos.

Gold Laus 2018: Dana Font

CLAP to the best experimental typography 2018: <u>Dana Font</u>

Award to Educational Innovation Group 2017: GIE Cyberaula

HackForGood 2016: Aprendis 1st award local by Telefónica. 1st award by U.Comillas. 3th award by Telefónica - UPM.

work experience

Capchase

Madrid, Spain. Dec 2020 - present.

Software developer

Involvement in different projects from frontend to backend developments. REST API, functionality design, UX implementation on the client platform and backoffice.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JS, ES6, React, Vue, TypeScript, Jest, Postman, MongoDB, SQL, Node.js & Express.

Bnext

Madrid, Spain. Sept 2019 - Dec 2020.

Backend developer

At Core Banking System Team. Design, develop, maintain and upgrade the integration of Bnext 2.0.: card life cycle, customer onboarding and registration, KYC, AML, third party gateways, REST API, microservices...

Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6, Jest, Postman, MongoDB, SQL, Nest.js, Node.js & Express.

BinPar Digital Ignition

Las Rozas, Madrid, Spain. March 2019 - Sept 2019.

Fullstack developer

Design, management and development of solutions for innovative projects. SEO optimization Improved e-commerce development with GA.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, SASS, JS, ES6, React, Apollo GraphQL, Next.js, MongoDB, Node.js, Express, Git & GitFlow.

GING UPM

Polytechnic University. Madrid, Spain. Sept 2017 - March 2019.

Frontend developer and UX-UI designer

UX-UI design, interface and product design responsible. Front-End development to interactive responsive solutions. Researcher in group projects in fields related to ITC development and use.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JS, React, WP, Bootstrap MongoDB, Node.js, Express. AdobeCC & iWork.

Barfutura

Madrid, Spain. Feb - July 2017.

Graphic designer

Branding and corporate identity. Photography, digital retouching and poster design. Layout, design and web development.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Wordpress, AdobeCC & iWork.

Derepente Madrid

Madrid, Spain. June - Nov 2016.

Graphic and web designer

Branding, corporate identity and advertising. Layout, design and web development, WordPress.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Wordpress, AdobeCC & iWork.

education

Ironhack - Web Development: Part-Time program.

SEPT18 - MAR19

Escuela Superior de Diseño de Madrid (ESD)

Master of Interactive Design. (UX - UI & web development). Bachelor degree of Graphic Design.

Escuela de Arte número diez

Higher Level Training Cycle on Artistic Photography.

SEPT11 - MAR14

SEPT17 - JUN18

SEPT13 - JUN17